### **Lynn Yang**

Full Stack Developer | Healthcare Professional

Once a frontline health care worker, now a full-stack developer specializing in both frontend and backend development. I am excited to get behind the desk, create solutions and solve problems for people. My goal is to merge the best of both worlds to help clients and organizations grow.

- **647-287-8916**
- https://klynnyang.github.io/portfolio/
- ☑ lynnyangnc@gmail.com
- in LynnYang
- klynnyang

### SKILLS

ReactJS	Javascript
Node.js	ExpressJS
Django	Python
HTML	CSS
JQuery	AJAX
Redux	Bootstrap
Materialize	Git

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**GitHub** 

Software Engineering	September
Immersive	2021
General Assembly	

**Typescript** 

April

2018

**Python Programming**General Assembly

June 2021

Medical Laboratory
Technologist (General)
College of Medical Laboratory
Technologist of Ontario (C.M.L.T.O)

#### **PROJECTS**

## Battleship | Javascript, HTML, CSS https://klynnyang.github.io/battleship/

- Developed a browser based game for users to play Battleship against computer AI.
- Javascript used in creating object oriented functions and event listeners were added for sprite manipulation.
- Utilized Figma for wireframe and Trello for managing tasks during development.

### Game Catalog | Node.js, ExpressJS, MongoDB, Google OAuth https://catalog-for-games.herokuapp.com/

- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations.
- Used Mongoose to define Schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Utilized Google OAuth for gmail login and Imgur API for uploading images.
- Used Lucidchart for planning ERD and Trello to track and manage MVP, ice box items and user stories.

# Expense-O-Track | Python, Django, Postgresql, JQuery, AJAX, Javascript, AllAuth

https://expense-o-track.herokuapp.com/

- Application utilizes the full stack framework Django and Python for full CRUD operations.
- Used the RDMS Postgresql to store data on the backend.
- Integrated AJAX request and jQuery with Django to allow web pages to update asynchronously.
- Plotted line graphs and bar charts with Chart.js, Javascript and JQuery.
- AllAuth utilized for email & social media log in.

## Paway | Javascript, React, Node.js, MongoDB https://paway.herokuapp.com/

- Collaboratory MERN stack SPA with full CRUD operations hitting all RESTful API calls
- Used Google Maps API and Places Autocomplete to find locations searched, translated to latitude, longitude and zip code, and mapped dynamically.
- Utilized Nodemailer JS for sending email notifications and react share API for social media share.
- Styled the visual aspect of the SPA with Bootstrap, MDB, Materialize UI and CSS3.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# OAHPP - Public Health Laboratory (Toronto) - Molecular Diagnostics/Virus Detection

(January 2019 -July 2021)

Medical Laboratory Technologist

- Maintained and operated the Real-Time PCR analyzer Cobas 8800/6800 for the detection of COVID-19.
- Reviewed QC results through Unity Real-Time and performed troubleshooting when QC fell out of acceptable ranges.
- Processed routine or STAT specimens and relayed results to responsible health care professionals within specified turn-around-time.

## UHN - Toronto General Hospital - Hematology Department Medical Laboratory Technologist (May 2018 - May 2020)

- Operated and performed maintenance on the SYSMEX XN-9000, CS-5100 and  $\,$ 

- Performed 100 cell differentials and malaria screen on peripheral blood smears.
- Reconstituted reagents and performed PT, aPTT, UFH, LMWH, D-Dimer, TT and Fibrinogen on the SYSMEX CS-5100 coagulation analyzer.
- Operated and performed semi-automated PT & aPTT on the STA Compact Max coagulation analyzer.
- Performed ESR, manual Reticulocyte Count, Sickle solubility, Malaria Rapid Screen, manual Hematocrit, UFE, and manual counts for RBC, WBC & PLT.
- Prepared cytospin slides for body fluids (Ascites, Pleural, Pericardial, Peritoneal, Synovial, Bronchial washing and CSF).

### **St. Michael's Hospital**Medical Laboratory Science Student

(September 2017 - February 2018)

• Interpreted culture results from blood cultures, wound swabs, sterile fluids, and non-sterile fluids.

 Performed E-test, Double Disc Diffusion, ERM gene and other sensitivity testing on microorganisms.

# OAHPP - Public Health Laboratory (Toronto) - Research Department

(May 2016 - August

Summer Research Student

- Investigated Streptococcus pyogenes (GBS) for a novel variant of the pilus island 1 backbone protein, the paper was published in the Journal of Medical Microbiology in 2017.
- Streaked GBS for overnight growth and harvested GBS into Todd-Hewitt broth for DNA extraction.
- Extracted GBS DNA, prepared PCR mastermix and performed multiplex PCR on the Thermo-cycler BioRad C1000 & S1000.
- Performed gel electrophoresis on 1% agarose gel followed by SYBR gold staining.

### EDUCATION

### **General Assembly**Software Engineering Immersive

(July 2021 - September 2021)

General Assembly

Python Programming

(February 2021 - April 2021)

The Michener Institute of Education at UHN

(September 2015 - March 2018)

Advanced Diploma Medical Laboratory Science

## University of Waterloo (September 2007 - May 2013) Bachelor of Science (Honors) Science